A villain will rise.
Minions: The Rise of Gru is a family, comedy,
adventure film directed by Kyle Balda.
A fanboy of a supervillain supergroup known as the Vicious 6, Gru hatches a plan to become
evil enough to join them, with the backup of his followers, the Minions.
Gru (voice), played by Steve Carell.
Kevin / Stuart / Bob / Minions (voice), played by Pierre Coffin.
Wild Knuckles (voice), played by Alan Arkin.
Belle Bottom (voice), played by Taraji P. Henson.
Gru's Mom (voice), played by Julie Andrews.
Jean Clawed (voice), played by Jean-Claude Van Damme.
Minions: The Rise of Gru is a 2022 American animated comedy film directed by Kyle
Balda and written by Matthew Fogel from a story by Fogel and Brian Lynch.
Produced by Illumination and distributed by Universal Pictures, it is the sequel to Minions (2015), a
prequel to Despicable Me (2010), and the fifth entry overall in the Despicable Me franchise.
It features Steve Carell reprising his role as Gru and Pierre Coffin as the Minions, along with Russell
Brand, Will Arnett, Steve Coogan and Julie Andrews reprising their respective roles as Dr.
Nefario, Mr.
Perkins, Silas Ramsbottom and Gru's mother Marlena.
New cast members include Taraji P.
Henson, Michelle Yeoh and Alan Arkin in his final film role.
In the film, an eleven-year-old Gru plans to become a supervillain with the help of his
Minions, which leads to a showdown with a malevolent team, the Vicious 6.
After being delayed for two years due to the COVID-19 pandemic, Minions: The Rise of Gru had its world premiere at the Annecy
International Animation Film Festival on June 13, 2022, and was theatrically released in the United States on July 1.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, some deemed it an improvement over its predecessor, with praise earned for its
score, animation, humor, voice performances (particularly Carell's), and aesthetic, although its plot was criticized.
It was also a commercial success, grossing over $940 million worldwide
and becoming the fifth-highest-grossing film of 2022.
A sequel is scheduled to be released on July 1, 2026.
The film explores themes of 1970s, villain,
sequel, spin off, duringcreditsstinger.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.